A Guide to the Governor Terry McAuliffe, Communications Office Records of Christina Nuckols, 2014-2016 (bulk 2014)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Terry McAuliffe, Communications Office Records of Christina Nuckols 2014-2016 (bulk 2014)
The Library of Virginia
53532
1.35 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 53532 transferred on 14 January 2022.
Historical Information
The Communications Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. The office was also responsible for making the Governor's public schedule, press releases, executive orders, proclamations, and selected speeches available online.
Governor McAuliffe originally named Jamie Radice as Communications Director. Brian Coy, who was originally Press Secretary, was promoted to this position upon Radice's departure in December of 2014.
Christina Nuckols, a long-time and very well thought of political journalist in Virginia who the administration had brought in to focus on media relations on Medicaid, moved from the Secretary of Health and Human Resources office into the governor's office as Deputy Communications Director. Coy continued as McAuliffe's lead spokesman, with Nuckols focused more on speech writing and other related matters.
Scope and Content
Governor Terry McAuliffe Communications Office Records of Christina Nuckols are housed in two archival boxes. The collection is comprised of one large series of Correspondence and Subject files, almost exclusively from 2014. These records include correspondence and email, speech and presentation drafts, memorandums, talking points, meeting minutes, and news clippings. These records document the activities of Deputy Communications Director, Christina Nuckols, focused on speech writing and Health Care initiatives such as Medicaid, A Healthy Virginia initiative and the Affordable Care Act. The two other major subjects of Nuckol's records are Restoration of Rights and the Governors Commission on Integrity and Public Confidence in State Government.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following subseries:
a. Budget and General Fund
b. Restoration of Rights
c. Virginia Museum of Fine Arts/Confederate Memorial (Pelham Chapel)
d. Notepads
e. Healthcare
f. Governor's Commission on Integrity and Public Confidence in State Government
Related Material
The Governor Terry McAuliffe Administration Web Archive Collection, 2014-2018
The Records of the Office of the Secretary of Administration, 2014-2018
The Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Press Office Records, 2004-2010
Contents List
- I. Correspondence, and Subject File Records of Christina Nuckols, 2014-2016 (bulk 2014)., Extent: 1.35 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 1-2)
  - Budget and General Fund
    - Governor's Speech - December, 2014 (1 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Speech - December, 2014 (2 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Presentations and Reports, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Proposals/Requests, 2014 (1 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Proposals/Requests, 2014 (2 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Restoration of Rights
    - Executive Order, April, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Town Hall, May, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Community Roundtable, June, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Announcement Remarks, August, 2016. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - VMFA/Confederate Memorial
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts/Confederate Memorial (Pelham Chapel), 2015. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Notepads
    This portion of box 1 (approximately .35 cubic feet) contains a group of loose notepads of various sizes with handwritten notes. The notepads are primarily undated and cover topics found in the other folders in this box and collection.
  - Healthcare
    - A Healthy Virginia, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Access, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP), 2014. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ebola Virus, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Family Health and Family Access to Medical Insurance Security (FAMIS), 2014. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Federal Open Enrollment, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Immunizations, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Innovation, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Maps and Graphics, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mental Health, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Outreach, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Prescription/Heroin Abuse, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Smoking, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Veterans, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Well Ahead Virginia, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Workforce (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Other, 2014 (1 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Other, 2014 (2 of 2). (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Governor's Commission on Integrity and Public Confidence in State Government
    - Ethics Remarks, 2015. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Forums, 2014. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Laws and Executive Orders, 2014 (1 of 2). (Folder 1)
    - Laws and Executive Orders, 2014 (1 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Laws and Executive Orders, 2014 (2 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Press, 2014 (1 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Press, 2014 (2 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Research from David Jones, 2014. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Supporting Documents, 2014 (1 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Supporting Documents, 2014 (2 of 2). (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 2015, (1 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 2015, (2 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 2015, (3 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 11)